Inventory of the Robert William Hughes Papers 1818-1900
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Inventory of the Robert William Hughes Papers 1818-1900
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 39.2 H87
103 items.
Papers, mainly 1865-1900, of Robert William Hughes (1821-1901), journalist, Republican politician, and United States District Judge, of Abingdon and Norfolk, Va.
Louis Agassiz,; Chester Alan Arthur,; George Bancroft,; Benjamin F. Butler (Benjamin Franklin),; Lewis Cass,; Claudius Crozet,; J.L.M. Curry(Jabez Lamar Monroe),; John Moncure Daniel,; J.D.B. De Bow(James Dunwoody Brownson),; Benjamin Stoddert Ewell,; Ulysses S. Grant (Ulysses Simpson),; J.B.H. (James Barron Hope),; Robert William Hughes,; G. P. R. James (George Payne Rainsford),; Joseph E. Johnston (Joseph Eggleston),; James Longstreet,; William Henry Fitzhugh Lee,; John Singleton Mosby,; Alfred Magill Randolph.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 103 items, 10/14/1937.
Biographical/Historical Information
Robert William Hughes was born at Muddy Creek Plantation, Powhatan County, Va. in 1821. His parents died in 1822 and he was raised by Edward C. Carrington and Eliza Preston Carrington. He attended Caldwell Institute, Greensboro, N. C. and studied law in Fincastle, Va. He married Eliza M. Johnston, niece of Joseph E. Johnston and the adopted daughter and niece of John B. Floyd. Hughes' son was Robert Morton Hughes. Robert William Hughes was a newspaper editor and federal district attorney. Involved in post Civil War Republican Party politics, he was nominated for governor of Virginia and for Congress but did not win. He was appointed judge of the federal court for the Eastern District of Virginia.
Chronology
16 Jan. 1821 Born at Muddy Creek Plantation, Powhatan Co., Va., the son of Jesse and Elizabeth Woodson (Morton) Hughes.
1822 Both parents died, and Hughes was raised by Gen. Edward C. Carrington and his wife, Eliza(Preston) Carrington of Halifax Co., Va.(family relationship not known).
Ca. 1833-1837 "put to the carpenter's trade in Princeton, N.J."
Ca. 1837-1838 Attended Caldwell Institute, Greensboro, N.C.
Ca. 1839 Tutor, Bingham High School, Hillsboro, N.C.
1843 Studied law, Fincastle, Va.
1846 Began practice of law, Richmond, Va.
4 June 1850 Married Eliza M. Johnston,(1825-1908), niece of Gen. Joseph E. Johnston and niece and adopted daughter of John Buchanan and Sarah (Preston) Floyd.
1850 Began writing editorials for the Richmond Examiner.
1853-1857 Editor of the Richmond Examiner while regular editor in Europe.
1855 Birth of son, Robert Morton Hughes.
1857-1861 Editor of the Washington Union, and lived in home of Secretary of War John Buchanan Floyd.
1861 Birth of son, Floyd Hughes(2 other children died young)
1861 Because of "chronic disease" retired to a farm near Abingdon, Va., where General and Mrs. Floyd 1ived with the Hughes family.
1861-1864 Wrote for the Richmond Examiner, showing hostility toward Jefferson Davis' administration.
1865-1866 Edited the Richmond Republic, and generally pursued a course that considered "nimble"
1868 Delegate to National Democratic Convention.
1869-1870 Editor of the Richmond State Journal.
Ca. 1870 Wounded William E. Cameron in a duel.
1872 Named federal district attorney by Grant administration.
1872 Nominated for Congress but did not win.
1873 Nominated for Governor of Virginia but did not win.
1874 Named Judge of federal court for the Eastern District of Va.
1898 Resigned judgeship.
1901 Died at Abingdon, Va.
Source: Dictionary of American Biography; Preston-Johnston-Floyd-Hughes genealogical chart.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, mainly 1865-1900, of Robert William Hughes (1821-1901), journalist, Republican politician, and United States District Judge, of Abingdon and Norfolk, Va. Included are family momentoes relating to Hughes' foster father, General Edward C. Carrington (1790-1855), and to Mrs. Hughes' father and brother, Charles C. (1795-1832) and John Preston Johnston (1821?-l847), articles written by Hughes on Virginia politics, newspapers, and horses, a few letters to Mrs. Hughes, and a scrapbook containing pamphlets and newspaper clippings of articles by Hughes or on subjects that interested Hughes, as well as a letter from J.H. Platt, Jr., Secretary, Union Congressional Republican Executive Committee, Washington, D.C., to Hughes, 17 Sept. 1870, concerning Virginia Republican politics.
Prominent correspondents include Louis Agassiz, Chester A. Arthur, George Bancroft, Benjamin F. Butler, Lewis Cass, Claudius Crozet, J.M.L. Curry, John Moncure Daniel, John Warwick Daniel, J.D.B. DeBow, Benjamin S. Ewell, Ulysses S. Grant, James Barron Hope, G.P.R. James, Joseph E. Johnston, W.H.F. Lee, James Longstreet, John S. Mosby, Bishop Alfred Magill Randolph, and William Fanning Wickham (concerning his father John Wickham and members of the Richmond Bar including John Marshall.)
Arrangement
Organization
This collection is organized into 2 Series: 1. Correspondence, and 2. Printed Material and Manuscript Volumes.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by date with those items without dates located at the end of the series. Series 1 is divided into subseries mostly by ten year increments.
Additional Related Materials
Related Materials at William And Mary
The John B. Floyd Papers, Robert Morton Hughes Papers, and Joseph E. Johnston Papers, are collections that relate to this collection, Robert William Hughes, which are located in Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
John B. Floyd Papers, Manuscripts and Rare Books Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary. John Buchanan Floyd Papers, 1831-1863, 1850- 1863.72 items.Collection number: Mss. 65 F59
Robert Morton Hughes Papers, Manuscripts and Rare Books Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary. Robert Morton Hughes Collection, 1715-1933, 1871- 1933.238 items.Collection number: Mss. 65 H88
Joseph E. Johnston Papers, Manuscripts and Rare Books Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary. Joseph E. Johnston Papers, 1825-1891.264 items.Collection number: Mss. 39.1 J63
Related Materials at Old Dominion University
Another related collection is the Robert Morton Hughes Papers, located in Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University. This collection in significant because of the correspondence and other papers originally belonging to several of Hughes' relatives including Judge Robert W. Hughes, Governor John B. Floyd, and General Joseph E. Johnston. The collection also contains personal and political correspondence regarding Robert Morton Hughes' legal practice, involvement in Virginia politics, activities in support of education, longtime association with the College of William and Mary, and service on the State Board of Education and the Board of Directors of the Norfolk Public Library.
Papers of Robert Morton Hughes, Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University, Norfolk, Virginia. Papers of Robert Morton Hughes, 1767-1959.39 Hollinger Flat Boxes; 5 Hollinger Oversized Boxes and Additional Bound Volumes.Collection number: MG-7
Index Terms
Family Names:
Persons:
Wickham, John, 1763-1839.; Marshall, John, 1755-1835.; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873.; Arthur, Chester Alan, 1829-1886.; Bancroft, George, 1800-1891.; Butler, Benjamin F. (Benjamin Franklin), 1818- 1893.; Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866.; Crozet, Claudius, 1790-1864.; Curry, J. L. M. (Jabez Lamar Monroe), 1825-1903.; Daniel, John Moncure, 1825-1865.; De Bow, J. D. B. (James Dunwoody Brownson), 1820-1867.; Ewell, Benjamin Stoddert, 1810-1894.; Grant, Ulysses S. (Ulysses Simpson), 1822-1885.; J. B. H. (James Barron Hope), 1829-1887.; James, G. P. R. (George Payne Rainsford), 1801?-1860.; Johnston, Joseph E. (Joseph Eggleston), 1807- 1891.; Longstreet, James, 1821-1904.; Lee, William Henry Fitzhugh, 1837-1891.; Mosby, John Singleton, 1833-1916.; Randolph, Alfred Magill, 1836-1918.
Subjects:
Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); Railroads--Virginia.; Canals--United States.; Harbors--United States.; Horses--Virginia.; United States--Politics and government-- 1865-1900.; United States-- History--Civil War, 1861-1865.
Occupations:
Lawyers--Virginia--Correspondence.; Practice of law--Virginia--History.
Components List
  Series 1: Correspondence
- Correspondence, 1818-1900, n.d. (Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence, 1810-1849., 4 items. (Folder 1)
    - Legal document signed by Arch[ibald] Stuart, Creed Taylor, and W[illia]m Daniel, granting permission to Charles C. Johnston [Mrs. R.W. Hughes' father] to practice law in the state of Virginia, 28 Feb[ruar]y 1818., 1 page. DS. (Folder 1)
    - J. P[reston] Johnstone [sic] [Johnston], [West Point, New York], to Eliza M. Johnstore [sic] [Johnston], [Abingdon, Virginia], 10 Aug. 1839., 3 pages. PL & ALS. (Folder 1)
      Invitation to a ball at West Point; and concerning the lack of letters from Eliza and relations.
    - J. P[reston] Johnstone [sic] [Johnston], West Point, [New York] to Eliza M. Johnstone [sic] [Johnston], Abingdon, Virginia, 6 Aug. 1842., 1 page. PLS. (Folder 1)
      Invitation to a West Point ball.
    - License for Edward C. Carrington [R.W. Hughes' foster father] to practice as counsel and attorney in Virginia, 8 June 1842., 1 page. DS. (Folder 1)
      Signed by W[illia]m H. Cabell, John B. Clopton [?], and P.M. Nicholas.
  - Correspondence, 1950-1959., 9 items. (Folder 1)
    - A.S. Johnston, n.p., to "his fair cousin" [Eliza M. Johnston], n.p., [ante 1850]., 1 page. AL. (Folder 1)
      Invitation to dinner written in the third person.
    - L. Agassiz, Cambridge, [Massachusetts], to R.W. Hughes, Richmond, [Virginia], 15 Oct. 1853., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Concerns Agassiz's proposed publication on the natural history of the fishes of the United States.
    - James McDowell, Lexington, Virginia, to Rob[er]t W. Hughes, Richmond, Virginia, 27 July 1854., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Discussion of a financial situation involving him [McDowell] as an administrator of a certain account.
    - Deed given by Robert W. Hughes to James H. Conway covering a tenement on 13th Street in the city of Richmond, 3 October 1854., 3 pages. ADS. (Folder 1)
    - George Bancroft, New York, [New York], to Ro[bert] W. Hughes, Richmond, Virginia, 16 Nov. 1855., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Concerning papers forwarded to R.W.H. received from Mr. Floyd.
    - Florence James, Richmond, Virginia, to Mrs. [Robert W.] Hughes, care of J[ohn] B. Floyd, Secretary of War, Washington, D.C., 23 Sept. 18[ca. 57-60]., 14 pages. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Concerning the Hughes' European trip and Richmond news, especially the Wise-Clement duel.
    - Ro[bert] W. Hughes, Washington, [D.C.], to Dr. Ja[me]s H. Conway, n.p., 10 April 1858., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Asks him to deposit interest due in the Exchange Bank in Richmond.
    - Lewis Cass, n.p., to [Robert W.] Hughes, n.p., 23 Feb. 1859., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Encloses informational abstract which he feels will be of sufficient importance to the public.
    - Ro[bert] W. Hughes, Abingdon, Virginia, to Dr. Ja[me]s H. Conway, n.p., 8 Oct. 1859., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Asks him to deposit in the Exchange Bank of Richmond the principal and interest due on Conway's purchase of a house.
  - Correspondence, 1960-1969., 12 items. (Folder 1)
    - Ro[bert] W. Hughes, Washington City [D.C.], to Dr. [James H.] Conway, n.p., 20 April 1860., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Asks Conway to deposit the semi-annual interest in the Exchange Bank in Richmond.
    - C. Crozet, Goodson, [Virginia], to R.W. Hughes, [Abingdon, Virginia?], 6 April 1861., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Concerns the construction of a railroad and difficulties encountered in obtaining materials.
    - John Fraser, Richmond, Virginia, to Robert W. Hughes, n.p., 16 Jan. 1862., 1 page. DS. (Folder 1)
      Receipt for $1150.00 for purchase of two negro slaves, Myra and child, Longa.
    - D.B. Baldwin, Capt. and Enrolling Officer for 13th Con[gressional] District, [Virginia], n.p., to Ro[bert] W. Hughes, n.p., 4 August 1863., 1 page. PDS. (Folder 1)
      Exemption from military service by reason of being an employee of the Richmond Examiner.
    - Pardon for R.W. Hughes for his part in the "rebellion against the Government of the United States" from Andrew Johnson with a surrogate signature of Andrew Johnson and signed by William H. Seward, Secretary of State, 26 Oct. 1865., 2 pages. PDS. (Folder 1)
    - J.D.B. DeBow, N[ew] York, [New York], to R.W. Hughes, Abingdon, Virginia, 20 Feb. 1866., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Concerning the cost of reprints of an article by Hughes in DeBow's Review.
    - Ro[bert] W. Hughes, Abingdon, Virginia, to Col. T.H. Ellis, n.p., 25 March 1866., 9 pages. ADfS. Including a TCy of 6 pages. (Folder 1)
      Regarding a canal from Virginia to the Ohio River.
    - H.J. Raymond, N[ew] Y[ork], [New York], to [R. W. Hughes], n.p., 1 May 1867., 3 pages. ALs. (Folder 1)
      Concerning "your letter" which throws light on the political situation in Virginia, expressing confidence in Grant and his election; requesting that "My Dear Sir" write a letter every week or ten days "on the varying aspects of affairs political, economical, social, and general in Virginia and the South ?"; and the temper of the Republican party.
    - Manton Marble, "The World" Office, New York, [New York], to R.W. Hughes, n.p., 25 March 1868., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Concerns a proposed literary work of Hughes and the enfranchisement of Negroes in the current political climate.
    - M.F. Maury, Office of Physical Survey, Richmond, Virginia, to R[obert] W. Hughes, Abingdon, Virginia, 17 Sept. 1868., 14 pages. LS. (Folder 1)
      Concerning ports and shipping on the East coast.
    - J.W. Forney, n.p., to Ro[bert] W. Hughes, n.p., [ca. 1869-1870]., 4 pages. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Expresses his sympathy to Hughes concerning the defeat of the Republican party in Virginia.
    - Benj[amin] F. Butler, Washington, [D.C.], to H.A. Bond, Richmond, Virginia, 14 M[ar]ch 1869., 1 page. LS. (Folder 1)
      Concerning the removal of political disabilities from Rob[er]t W. Hughes.
  - Correspondence, 1870-1879., 28 items. (Folder 1-2)
    - John W. Brockenbrough, Lexington, Virginia, to Col. R.W. Hughes Abingdon, Virginia, 29 April 1871., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Thanks Hughes for the check for $350.00 and his expressions of congratulations on the restoration of his health.
    - G.C. Walker [Governor of Virginia], to Col. R[obert] W. Hughes, n.p., 7 Sept. 1871., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Discusses Virginia state finances.
    - Geo[rge] H. Williams, Department of Justice, Washington, [D.C.], to R[obert] W. Hughes, U.S. Attorney, Abingdon, Virginia, 18 Dec. 1872., 2 pages. LS. (Folder 1)
      Concerns the resignation of Mr. Slater as Hughes' assistant.
    - John W. Johnston, Abingdon, [Virginia] to R.W. Hughes, n.p., 27 Dec. 1872., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Discusses his financial concerns, including meeting a note due to Hughes in January.
    - W.G. Brownlow, Knoxville, [Tennessee.],to R.W. Hughes, Abingdon [Virginia], 27 May 1873., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Asks Hughes' support of his nephew, Henry C. Brownlow, of Abingdon, for the office of Postmaster.
    - Alex Rules [?], Ionia, Louisa County, [Virginia], to Col. [Robert W.] Hughes, n.p., 14 July 1873., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Requests Hughes to prepare resolutions and an address for party platform. Believes Hughes will be nominated without serious opposition.
    - James Longstreet, Lynchburg, Virginia, to R.W. Hughes, n.p., 3 Sept. 1873., 4 pages. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Concerning the charges made by Col. Withers in his "Warrenton speech" against Longstreet.
    - John F. Lewis, House of Representatives, Washington, D.C., to Judge [Robert W. Hughes], n.p., 14 Jan 1874., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Thanks Hughes for his note of acknowledgment of his [Lewis'] favor [confirmation of Hughes as Judge].
    - James H. Platt, Jr., House of Representatives, Washington, D.C., to R.W. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 29 March 1874., 1 page. LS. (Folder 2)
      Asks Hughes to return Hambleton's Life of Wise.
    - Jos[eph] Segar, Washington [D.C.], to R.W. Hughes, n.p., 31 March [18]74., 3 pages. AL. (Folder 2)
      Requests Hughes' assistance in obtaining a government position.
    - Joseph P. Bradley, Washington, [D.C.], to [R.W. Hughes?], 11 Dec. 1874., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Acknowledges receipt of opinion regarding the Petersburg, [Virginia] election cases.
    - D.W. Lynch, n.p., to Judge R[obert] W. Hughes, "at Home," 12 January [18]75., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Complains about the condition of the division fence between Hughes and Lynch's mother.
    - Z[achariah] Chandler, Secretary, Department of the Interior, Washington, [D.C.], to R[obert] W. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 1 April 1876., 1 page. LS. (Folder 2)
      Requesting information about possible charges against L.H. Chandler.
    - John S. Mosby, Washington, D.C., to R[obert] W. Hughes, n.p., 19 April 1876., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Concerning the postponement of an appointment until the President [Grant] can see Hughes.
    - Roscoe Conkling, United States Senate Chamber, Washington [D.C.], to R[obert] W. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 23 June 1876., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Thanking Hughes for his letter and generous interest.
    - Geo[rge] B. Harrison, Richmond, Virginia, to Mrs. R[obert] W. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 27 Sept. 1876., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Encloses autograph of W[illiam] H[enry] Harrison as frank on envelope addressed to Benjamin Harrison, Berke1ey, Charles City C[ourt] H[ouse], Virginia, and postmarked Washington, D.C., 18 March, New York, giving details and authentification.
    - U.S. Grant, Washington, [D.C.], to R.W. Hughes, U.S. District Judge of the Eastern District of Virginia, n.p., 4 Nov. 1876., 1 page. LS. (Folder 2)
      Concerning Hughes' attendance at Petersburg, Virginia, in November for the purposes mentioned in Section 1988 of said Revised Statutes.
    - Geo[rge] S. Bryan, Charleston, S.C., to R[obert] W. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 3 March [18]77., 4 pages. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Regrets to inform Hughes that he really has "very little, indeed of all that I have to me, that is worthily embodied," [for publication], relating to his work.
    - M[orrison] R[emick] Waite, Charleston, S.C., to Ro[bert] W. Hughes, n.p., 22 May 1877., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Discussion of upcoming resignation of Forbes[?] and filling the vacancy. Also relates opinions in the "Olen case."
    - D[avid] M[cKendree] Key, Post Office Department, Washington, [D.C.], to R.W. Hughes, n.p., 9 June 1877., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Concerning the appointment of Mr. Potts as Postmaster at Petersburg; Hughes' letter on the Petersburg matter has been referred to the President [Grant].
    - Geo[rge] F[ranklin] Edmunds, United States Senate Chamber, Washington, [D.C.], to R.W. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 26 Dec. 1877., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Received Hughes' note, and is appreciative of his verification of the state of things [?], even though sorrowful.
    - Cha[rle]s Devens, Washington, [D.C.], to Robert W. Hughes, n.p., 25 March [18]78., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Has received Hughes' opinion of the Lee vs. Kaufman case, and is appreciative.
    - W[illia]m J. Robertson, Charlottesville, Virginia, to Robert W. Hughes, [Norfolk, Virginia?], 26 March 1878., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Concerning the Arlington case and Hughes' conclusive opinions to which "You can, I think, safely afford to rest your judicial reputation upon it" and Robertson's plan to attend the sale of the C. & 0. Railroad in Virginia, on the 2nd of April.
    - Bela M. Hughes, Denver, Colorado, to Rob[er]t W. Hughes, n.p., 7 Oct. [18]78., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Concerning the trial of Dr. Baylor[?] in Denver, Co., and Bela Hughes' grandfather who lived in Augusta Co., Virginia
    - Jo[h]n Jay Knox, Office of Comptroller of the Currency, Treasury Department, Washington, [D.C.], to R.W. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 15 Oct. 1878., 2 pages. LS. (Folder 2)
      Acknowledges receipt of two newspaper articles by Hughes concerning currency questions.
    - W[illia]m F[anning] Wickham, near Hanover C[our]t House, [Virginia], to R[obert] W. Hughes, n.p., 20 March 1879., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Reminisces about his father and his friends, including John Marshall, William Wirt, George Hay, William Call, George K. Taylor, and others, and their days as members of the Bar.
    - R[andall] L[ee] Gibson, White Sulphur Springs, W. Virginia, to [Robert W. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia], 19 Sept. 1879., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Hopes to visit him and Mrs. Hughes in Norfolk.
    - [William Preston, Lexington, Kentucky], to Ro[bert] W[illiam] Hughes, [Norfolk, Virginia?], 25 Sept. 1879., 8 pages. AL. (signature clipped). (Folder 2)
      Concerning the Arlington case and Mr. Willoughby's brief.
  - Correspondence, 1880-1889., 22 items. (Folder 2-3)
    - J[ames] B[radley] Thayer, Cambridge, Massachusetts, to R[obert] W. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 13 Ap[ri] 1 1880., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Discusses texts and methods of teaching lectures used at Harvard Law School, at which he is a professor.
    - W[illia]m Green, Richmond, [Virginia], to Robert W. Hughes, n.p., 2 June 1880., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Reference question concerning legal books and their whereabouts.
    - John Sherman, Treasury Department, Washington, [D.C.] to Ro[ber]t W. Hughes, n.p., 14 Dec. 1880., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Concerning John Tyler, Jr.'s request to provide a position for a Mr. Spitzer, the President's [R.B. Hayes] concurrence, and Sherman's election to the Senate.
    - J[ames] B[arron] H[ope], n.p., to R.W. Hughes, n.p., [ca. 1880]., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Congratulations to Mr. and Mrs. Robby [R.W. Hughes] on the arrival of a little boy.
    - T.C. Platt, New York, [New York], to Judge [Robert W. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia], 3 Feb. 1881., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Concerning Republican politics and the Presidential election of 1880.
    - Benj[amin] S. Ewell, College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, Virginia, to Robert W. Hughes, n.p., 24 March 1881., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Thanks Hughes for a copy of a letter he wrote and states his desire to use it, if published, to teach the students at William and Mary.
    - Ja[me]s G. Field, Attorney General's Office, Richmond, Virginia, to R[obert] W. Hughes, n.p., 28 Ap[ri]1 1881., 10 pages. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Concerning a thank you for "A Chapter of Personal and Political History," written by Hughes. Comments about conclusions reached by RWH in article, and Field's explanation of his differing view of certain points in the article.
    - M.E.R., Oxford, [England], to Mrs. Judge [Eliza M. (Johnston)] Hughes, Abingdon, Virginia, 1 Aug. [18]18., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Lists the itinerary of her travels in Ireland, Scotland, and England; has enjoyed seeing the autographs of great men.
    - James Barron Hope, Norfolk, [Virginia], to Mrs. R.W. Hughes, Abingdon, Virginia, 23 Oct. 1881., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 2)
      Is sending the Landmark with extracts from his verses.
    - Chester A. Arthur, Executive Mansion, Washington, [D.C.], to Robert W. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 17 January 1882., 1 page. LS. (Folder 3)
      Received Hughes' letter of the 7th and will give it due consideration.
    - Benjamin Harris Brewster, Department of Justice, Washington, D.C., to R.W. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 20 March 1882., 1 page. TLS. (Folder 3)